<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Footballs on Andi Skrgat</title>
    <link>https://as51340.github.io/blog/football/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Footballs on Andi Skrgat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://as51340.github.io/blog/football/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Football analysis products part II</title>
      <link>https://as51340.github.io/blog/football/football_analysis_products_part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as51340.github.io/blog/football/football_analysis_products_part2/</guid>
      <description>There are two types of data you can work with when doing football analysis. The first type is tracking data which provides us with information about the position of every player and the ball at every moment of the match. Such data is already enough to extract a variety of statistical info related to players such as distance covered, number of sprints, sprint classification into categories, player speed and acceleration through time etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to statistical football analysis</title>
      <link>https://as51340.github.io/blog/football/introduction_to_football_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://as51340.github.io/blog/football/introduction_to_football_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Two categories of products used in the industry can be identified. First category of products mainly deal with a support for event tagging and drawing visualizations. One of the best examples of a first category is Once, the product which has the possibility to tag actions based on the information about action&amp;rsquo;s end result.
StatsPerform is a main representative of the second category of products supporting ball and player tracking. Except for an incredible amount of information it can provide analysts with, such platform allows analysis of opponent team without any GPS devices required.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
